Cameron Bloomfield

PERSONAL STATEMENT

As a highly motivated individual with a background in chemical engineering and experience in e-commerce, logistics, and entrepreneurship, I have found a new passion in coding and am pursuing the Northcoders coding bootcamp to gain full-stack development skills. My unique blend of technical and entrepreneurial experience allows me to approach development projects from multiple perspectives to provide innovative solutions.

EXPERIENCE

Northcoders Coding Bootcamp — Trainee Software Developer

NOVEMBER 2022 - MARCH 2023

- Gained a strong understanding of front-end and back-end development, including HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, and Node.
- Acquired hands-on experience building full-stack web applications using modern web technologies.
- Developed the ability to work with databases and implement CRUD operations.
- Improved problem-solving skills through hands-on coding projects.

Logistics Business — Part-Owner w/ Various Roles

SEPTEMBER 2021 - OCTOBER 2022

- Secured and maintained a contract with Yodel for courier services.
- Conducted sales activities to acquire clients.
- Developed and practiced Agile methodology using Scrum to manage projects and ensure timely delivery of results.
- Implemented preventative planning measures to ensure smooth operations.

Vintage Clothing Business — Owner

DECEMBER 2019 - SEPTEMBER 2021

- Achieved a turnover of £35,000 in 2 years and verified as a top seller on Depop.
- Utilized creative photography and social media management to promote products and increase customer engagement.
- Negotiated stock purchases and managed financial records.
- Delivered exceptional customer service, promptly addressing inquiries and resolving issues resulting in 350+ positive reviews.

EDUCATION

$Newcastle\ University\ -$ Bachelor of Chemical Engineering - 1st Class Honors

SEPTEMBER 2018 - JUNE 2021

- Strong analytical and problem-solving skills developed through complex coursework in thermodynamics, process design, and material and energy balances.
- Experience using simulation software, such as Aspen and MATLAB, to model and optimize chemical processes.
- Ability to work in a team environment, including leading group projects.
- Familiarity with statistical analysis, data visualization, and process control.

Duchess Community High School — Six Form

- 3 A-levels in Chemistry, Physics, Mathematics (A, A, A)
- 12 A* to C grades in GCSEs (A* in Mathematics, B in Computer Science)

Gateshead 07975 716698 cam.w.bloomfield@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/cam-bloom

SKILLS

Programming LanguagesJavaScript (ES6), HTML5, CSS3, SQL, MATLAB

Libraries & Frameworks

React, Node JS, Express, PostgreSQL, Jest, Axios, Git

Design

Photoshop, AutoCAD, Canva

PROJECTS

Portfolio

A collection of all my projects.

https://cam-bloom.netlify.app

GitHub

All source code for my projects.

https://github.com/Cam-Bloom

News Website

Web app built with React, using the News API to display articles.

https://bloom-news.netlify.app

News API

API built using Express and PostgreSQL, implementing CRUD operations.

https://github.com/Cam-Bloom/BE-News-API

VOLUNTEERING

RNLI Volunteer

APRIL 2017 - JANUARY 2019
As a lifeboat operator, I responded to emergency call-outs and provided lifesaving assistance, while collaborating with the crew to maintain safe and efficient operation of the lifeboat through equipment preparation and maintenance.

INTERESTS

Amateur boxing, running and reading

REFERENCES AVAILABLE UPON REQUEST